Thomas Clarke

tom@tombclarke.co.uk | linkedin.com/in/tombclarke | tombclarke.co.uk

Profile:

A degree in Computer Science is allowing me to explore my interests and fuel my passion for technology. I am task focused, have a positive attitude and an industrious work ethic, all of which are important for my degree and for the real world of work. I have worked in several different working environments, all of which are giving me new experiences to help build myself and prepare me for my future. I can adapt to new environments quickly and deal with problems effectively.

Qualifications:

Currently studying: University of Birmingham - BSc in Computer Science with a Year in Industry - September 2014 to July 2018

- 1st Year Results Year average was 85%: Robotics (100%), Software Engineering (78%), Software Workshop Java (95%), Language and Logic (85%), Web Programming (88%), Foundations of Computer Science (with functional programming in OCaml) (82%), Artificial Intelligence (77%), Information Engineering (73%) and Multimedia Data (70%).
- **2**nd **Year Modules**: Software Systems Components, Functional Programming (in Haskell), Professional Computing, Mathematical Techniques for Computer Science, Computational Vision, Modules of Computation, Team Project, Computer Systems and Architecture, C/C++ and Computer Security.

John Cleveland College - September 2010 to August 2014

- A Levels: Mathematics (A*), Physics (A), I.C.T. (A), AS History (C), EPQ (A).
- GCSEs: 3 A*s, 6 As, 1 B and OCR Level 2 National Double Award in I.C.T. (Distinction).

Technical Skills:

- Strong programming in **Java** (good experience with the Eclipse IDE).
- Working knowledge of C# (used in Unity), MATLAB, OCaml, Haskell, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (including jQuery and D3.js), PHP and SQL.
- Experience with designing and creating experimental data visualisations (labs.majestic.com).
- Learning C/C++ in spare time and taking a C/C++ module in Q1 2016.
- Interest in security: member of the university's Hacking Society and taking module in Q1 2016.
- Programming robots using LeJOS.
- Good experience with version control system Git.
- Basic knowledge of Android Development and Visual Basic.

Technical Work History:

- Software Developer, Majestic, July to September 2015: Using various web technologies and utilising D3.js, me and a team of 2 other developers are using the Majestic API to create data visualisations. The work can be seen at labs.majestic.com. I also represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015.
- Web Developer, Hinckley Homeless group, September 2015, Voluntary: I created a new website for Hinckley Homeless Group to replace their original one using an agile approach to development. The website is hinckleyhomeless.com.
- Software Tester, Crane Electronics Ltd., Summer 2014: Exploring and testing a range of products to identify faults or problems and reporting them to the software engineer for revision. The main project was black box testing on an Android based device.

Thomas Clarke

tom@tombclarke.co.uk | linkedin.com/in/tombclarke | tombclarke.co.uk

Work History:

- Supervisor (promoted from sales assistant March 2015), Spar, October 2014 to present: Responsibilities include supervising sales assistants, opening, closing and operating the shop, handling money, and handling customer queries.
- Garden Centre Assistant, Woodlands Nursery & Garden Centre, October 2013 to January 2014: Responsibilities involved fast-paced customer service and till working.

Achievements and Interests

- While at Majestic our best project used data on 50,000 Twitter accounts and displayed them
 in a sunburst diagram and I also worked on integrating Twitter into the project. The project
 was received excellently, and they used their trade mark 'Social Explorer' on it as well as
 pushing it out as a headline on their blog and newsletters.
- Being a proactive player in a team competing in the Game Development society's game jams.
- Attending various hackathons:
 - BrumHack 3.0 where our team created a webpage which took any picture, used Clarifai's (<u>clarifai.com</u>) vision technology to get tags about what was in the picture, queries Wikipedia for more information and images and displayed the results to the user in an interactive D3 project.
 - I represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015 (<u>leedshack.org</u>) as a sponsor, where I gave
 a short introductory presentation on Majestic, and worked with the attendees on
 using the Majestic API in their projects.
 - BrumHack 2.0 where our team created a fast-paced fighting game in Unity using C# and having to create extra C# programs to run within the game to gather information about various websites using Majestic's API.
- Member of the Computer Science, Games Development, and Hacking societies at university.
- **Tutored students** in GCSE Computing and A-Level Mathematics.
- I have participated in extra circular activities including:
 - o An Extended Project Qualification (EPQ) based on creating an Android Application,
 - A Silver Crest Award based on Astronomy,
 - A v50 volunteering award.
- Bass guitar (achieved Merit at Grade 3).
- Socialising, live music, and travelling.

References:

- University of Birmingham Computer Science:
 - Hamid Dehghani
 - o Tel: +44 (0)121 414 8728
 - o Email: H.Dehghani@cs.bham.ac.uk
- Majestic-12 Ltd:
 - Steve Pitchford
 - o Email: stevep@majesticseo.com